# Lee Allen Digital design & development leader

## Summary

By combining modern front end development expertise, strong design background, and excellent communication skills, I lead teams to create user-centered, engaging, performant web and mobile products. I've helped companies large and small including: Allstate Insurance, Discover Financial Services, Ford Motor Company, Motorola Mobility, and PIMCO.

## Experience

## **PogoTec**

### Newport Beach, California (2017-present)

PogoTec is a wearable technology startup focused on creating products that work with a customer's style.

## Director of Digital Design & Development

As a founding member of the Digital Marketing & eCommerce team, I wear many hats including: UX Designer, UX Engineer, Project Manager, and office IT.

- Identify resource gaps, create hiring documentation, and build team of UX Designers, UI Designers, Design Researchers, and UX Engineers to take all web work in-house from agencies
- Create, implement, and run sprint-based iterative design and development workflow for web team to keep the team focused through frequently changing demands and tight deadlines
- Choose, setup, create documentation for, and manage all internal tools to facilitate collaboration for a team of in-office and remote workers
- Create and maintain web product roadmap including combining disparate micro-sites, launching eCommerce, and preparing for international expansion
- Create payment, fulfillment, and reverse logistics solutions to launch the company's first product
- Choose, setup, and manage all third-party website services to provide the business with the analytics it needs on an appropriate budget for an early-stage startup
- Manage all A/B testing including a test that increased conversions by 400%
- Hands-on creation of new web functionality when appropriate including documentation and development
- · Contribute to software team by writing PRDs for new mobile app features

## Motorola Mobility

Chicago, Illinois (2014-2016)

Motorola Mobility is a worldwide designer, manufacturer, and distributor of Android smartphones that was acquired by Google.

### Principal UX Engineering Manager

My team of UX Engineers was responsible for all high-fidelity (web and mobile app) prototyping, complex web A/B tests, rapid development of new web functionality, and being the liaison between design and development teams.

- Created high-fidelity prototypes using React for web and mobile apps, including
  Moto Maker, the award-winning phone customization platform, and Moto Display, the
  first always-on Android lock screen. This enabled rapid and more useful user testing
  feedback, reduced documentation work for design, and allowed our off-site engineering
  team to more accurately create the design team's intent.
- Created an A/B testing process that brought together Design, Product Management, and IT teams to gather testing needs, prioritize tests, manage deployment, and take action on results, while increasing overall testing velocity
- Made complex A/B tests with JavaScript that resulted in significant business improvements including: cancelling a six-figure product rendering improvement project by

# Lee Allen Digital design & development leader

## Experience

proving it would not increase conversions, increasing revenue by abandoning full-browser-height content sections, increasing revenue 15% by reordering product page content sections, and doubling revenue by using a different art direction for photography

- Designed, developed, and launched a short-term compare products page that increased conversions by 50%
- Redeveloped 360° product viewers to decrease their loading time by 500%
- Revamped process for creating tens of thousands of product renders for Moto Maker resulting in higher fidelity, faster creation, 80% reduction in final web file size, and lower production costs. I analyzed issues with previous process and coordinated with Industrial Design, Product Management, and IT to create the new solution.
- Created Kanban-based process for all UX team projects resulting in easier tracking of progress and improved ability to handle ever-changing requirements

## Acquity Group, part of Accenture Interactive

Chicago, Illinois (2008-2014)

Acquity Group is a nationwide eCommerce and digital marketing consultancy based in Chicago that was acquired by Accenture Interactive. I advanced through multiple roles during my time in the Front End Development practice as I helped it grow from 4 to 45 members nationwide.

## Senior Front End Development Manager (2012–2014)

I led front end development from early design concepts through deployment, creating Angular web apps, Cordova-based hybrid-mobile apps, and eCommerce websites.

- Created a tablet app using Angular for a major clothing retailer to allow shoppers to virtually create outfits that match their style, replacing a slow in-person process
- Was front end architect on a connected car project for a major American automaker that
  created responsive web, iOS, Android apps from the same codebase to remotely control
  and locate a line of electric cars, integrated with Adobe Experience Manager for easy
  content updates. Adobe engineers praised it as and integration that had "never been
  done before"
- Took over as front end manager and architect on a hybrid mobile app (web, iOS, and Android) for a major regional utility that was weeks behind schedule. I restructured the team and codebase to deliver a solution with 95% code sharing between platforms.
- Led front end practice's embrace of modern front end tooling and single-page applications
- Worked closely with user experience, visual design, and back end development team members to ensure front end development best practices were followed
- Built strong relationships with clients from initial pitches through product launches
- · Mentored multiple junior and senior developers as their Career Advisement Manager
- Participated in business development pursuits of Fortune 500 companies helping to secure tens of millions of dollars' worth of work

## Front End Development Manager (2011-2012)

 Lead technical architect for eight-figure mobile agency of record account with Fortune 100 financial services firm. Managed, architected, and developed multiple mobile web and hybrid iOS/Android Cordova projects including bringing their first tablet app to market

## Senior Front End Developer (2008-2011)

- Built mobile-optimized sites for multiple clients including regional rail authority site used by millions of customers daily to plan their commute
- Made an interactive connected car dashboard for a top-5 national insurance company
- Created component-based front ends for multiple clients including the world's largest

## Lee Allen Digital design & development leader

## Experience

bond trading firm and two Fortune 500 biotech companies

· Started and built internal mobile device testing lab to over 75 devices

## The Vertebrae Group

Marion, Illinois (2007-2008)

The Vertebrae Group is a web design, development, and social media consultancy based in Southern Illinois that I co-founded with two other partners.

- · Designed eCommerce website and Flash application UIs for multiple clients including an international beverage conglomerate and a national magazine publication
- · Developed websites using standards-compliant HTML, CSS, and JavaScript while everyone else optimized for IE6

## **Evolution Multimedia Corporation**

Herrin, Illinois (2002-2007)

Evolution Multimedia was a web design and development agency founded in 1996 with offices in Southern Illinois and St. Louis, Missouri.

## Hybrid UI Designer/Developer

- · Designed and developed UIs for websites, Flash applications, and client-server applications
- · Transitioned company to standards-based, hand coded front end development
- · Led UI design for a multi-million dollar gaming startup

## Education Certified ScrumMaster® (CSM)

Scrum Alliance

## Bachelor of Fine Arts in Communication Design

Southern Illinois University, Carbondale

## Awards 2015 Webby Awards

Consumer Electronics Website Honoree for Moto Maker

### 2001 Phi Ro Pi National Forensics Tournament

- · Silver Medal in Extemporaneous Speaking
- · Silver Medal in Impromptu Speaking
- · Bronze Medal in Informative Speaking

## 2000 Phi Ro Pi National Forensics Tournament

· Bronze Medal in Impromptu Speaking